I'm definitely not the smartest person
in the room and I can assure you that
because [music] otherwise my story would
have not been from Dunkin Donuts to
successful trader. It could have been
from engineer [music] to successful
trader, doctor to successful trader. But
what if I told you that precisely that
reason is why I am a consistent
profitable [music] trader because I
trade like an idiot. So that's what
we're going to be doing in this video
here today. We're going to remove
everything that you know about trading,
throw it into the bin, and start from
scratch with a simple approach that
anybody, even an idiot, can literally
learn and become successful with. And
you're going to stick to this approach
until you are consistently profitable
with this approach until then you can
add new things. Very simple. It's like
learning a new language. In order
[music] for you to speak the Mandarin
language fluently, you would first need
to learn the lettering. You would first
need to learn how to pronounce the
words, then how to read sentences, and
then how you can have a fluent
conversation after some time that you
have practiced it. You have to strip
everything down to the bone and learn
from scratch the correct way. So that's
what we're going to be doing in this
video here today. And the main reason
why this approach works is because it is
extremely simple and people simply
overlook it. This is literally one time
frame, one setup, one entry rule, and
one session. That is it. And I'm going
to break down how you guys can use this
right now. problem why people don't
succeed with this is because they over
complicate it with information overload.
It's like, oh well, if this time frame
says this, what about this time frame?
And what about the news events? And what
about the crossber correlation? And what
about this strategy's entry signal? And
what about this this this? They have too
much information. And they want to have
this external information affect this
one simple approach. Trading like an
idiot, you don't take any of that into
account. You just trade for that one
simple approach and stick to it and
that's it. I can't stress to you how
many times I've reviewed traders trades
and they love adjusting their stop-
loss. [music] They love having extra
confirmations into their position for no
reason that they can explain. They love
to close their trades early. They love
to have negative [music] riskrewards.
They love to have everything that
literally works against them in order
for them to become a profitable [music]
trader because they have learned all of
this external information that could
[music] potentially work for other
strategies if they were to just stick to
one. But they're bringing this external
information to a functional strategy
because it is too simple and they're
over complicating it and that is why
[music] they're not successful because
they're adding external strategies to a
working strategy because they can't
fathom how simple the [music] strategy
is going to be. Now step one into
learning this strategy that I'm about to
break down in this video. We can call it
the idiot strategy that simply works.
[music] Step one is going to be do not
get shiny object syndrome. Yes, [music]
you need to be aware and conscious that
there is tens of different if not
hundreds, [music] thousands of different
of strategies out there, different entry
signals, different trading approaches,
different [music] takes profit stock.
There's everything that is difference
and you need to accept that and be okay
and don't get shiny object [music]
syndrome when you don't find an
opportunity with this specific approach
at the specific [music] day that you
want to trade. All you need to do with
step one is not get distracted with
these other [music] strategies that are
out there in the market. be aware that
they're there, but you have your [music]
own strategy. Like, if you were to get a
brand new car, you just got a new car
yourself. [music] Yes, there's a
thousand different models out there, but
those don't matter. What matters is the
one that you have, and you need to stick
to it. [music] So, what is this car of
yours that you just got? You may ask
that you should not have any eyes for
any other cars on the road. Well, this
is going to be the simplest [music]
approach that you can possibly have.
It's going to be one pair, one time
frame, one session, and [music] one
entry signal. That is it. If you have
these four concepts in order for you to
enter a position, you're going to be
trading like an idiot. You're going to
have the simplest approach in the
market. And I can nearly guarantee you,
you will be more successful than 99% of
the traders that go on YouTube and try
to build a Frankenstein of a strategy
with all of this information that they
know because they simply don't know how
to put it all together. And it just
won't work. The more things you throw at
the chart doesn't mean the more money
you're going to make. The simpler you
trade, the more money you're going to
make because you have one specific
approach that repeats itself time and
time again. There's a consistency in
this approach. So, I'm about to break
this down right now for you guys. This
is the one strategy that you're going to
get married with until you're having
small consistent results. Then you can
start improving things for larger
trades, larger takeprofits, and other
options in the market. But you need to
have something that works at the core no
matter what. And if you don't want to
change it or add a different strategy,
you don't have to. You can 100% just
stick to this. This is more than enough.
Let me break it down for you guys. So,
moving on to the first step of the
actual strategy is picking the first
step, which is the pair. So, this step
is a bit subjective to how you like to
trade. So, there's obviously tens,
hundreds, thousands of different markets
that you can pick to trade from. And the
first step is picking one of these
markets. And you need to get married to
that one market. Not get the shiny
object syndrome. See another market
that's having a crazy move and then have
this same approach to then that market.
Can that work? Yes. But that is not your
focus right now. You need to stick to
one market, one session, one time frame,
and one entry signal. So there's many
different markets out there. You
obviously have markets like gold for
example which they tend to be extremely
volatile and they have very fastmoving
pairs but also quite heavily influenced
by the fundamentals. You have the S&P
500. The S&P 500 is also very heavily
influenced by the fundamentals but
market is trading kind of by all-time
highs. There's a lot of uncertainty.
Might not make the most sense to trade
there. It might. It really depends what
it makes the most sense for you. Then
you have other exotic pairs like Euro
AUD which these pairs move quite fast
very strong pip value moves and there's
tens of different of markets just like
EuroUSD there's tens of difference of
markets just like gold for example that
are very very volatile you could trade
gas you could trade oil there's just
different markets that you can pick from
and this really comes down to what type
of trader do you want to be you want to
be a higher time frame trader want to be
a lower time frame trader you want to
have very volatile moves are influenced
by the fundamentals. Would you rather
have moves that just move based off of
patterns and what you're seeing in the
chart in front of you? For me
personally, what makes the most sense is
trading off of patterns that are
happening right in front of you and not
having anything external influence
significantly my trade. So that's why if
I were to have to pick one market out of
all of these markets right here that are
in the markets, it would be EuroUSD.
EuroUSD might be slower moving in terms
of pips, but I can get great
risk-to-reward and it's extremely
predictable patterns. It's the most
volatile in terms of liquidity traded
market in the world. So, the cost to
take trades on this market are very low.
There is very low spreads, very low
commissions. It's just a very coste
effective market to trade and it would
be the market that I would pick from,
for example, based off of my experience.
And personally, this is the market that
I recommend that any beginner that is
their first time taking a trading
approach like this because again,
[music] it's the simplest, most cost
effective and you will have yourself
seeing these patterns happening very
frequently. So, I recommend this to any
beginner. Now, moving on to the next
step of the strategy is the actual time
frame. So, as you guys know, same way
how there's tens of difference of
markets out there to trade from, there's
tens of different time frames to trade
on, which is quite interesting this
crossorrelation because you could look
at the exact same markets in many
different scopes. You could look at it
with a big scope view. You could zoom in
up to every single second that the
market were to have a tick from. You
know, you can really zoom in as close as
the 1 second market, which really is
quite unnecessary. You don't need to
look at every single second close of the
market, every single minute. Truly makes
no sense. And you can look as far as
every single 12 months where every
single candlestick takes an entire year
to build, which is quite excessive. And
[music] at the beginning for any trader,
this could be quite complex because what
you're taught and [music] which is the
more experienced and advanced way to
trade is trading all of these time
frames in correlation, which is what's
called top- down analysis, which by the
way, we have one of those videos that we
break it down on this video. You want to
see it, just hit that like and subscribe
button so you guys can watch many other
videos just like this one. But top down
analysis is how you trade all of these
time frames together, which is a
different approach, which is more
advanced. And [music] it's not what this
video is about. This video is picking
one time frame only, which keeps things
a lot simpler and will probably even
make you more successful because you
would just have a [music] very specific
approach time and time again. So the
higher the time frame you are, keep in
mind that the longer the move will
[music] take. The lower the time frame
you are, the quicker the move you will
have. The problem is the higher the time
frame, the stronger the confirmation.
The lower the time frame, the weaker
[music] the confirmation. So these
things compensate each other a bit in
terms of balancement. So would you
rather have slower moving pairs [music]
but better confirmation of winning,
which you might take one trade a week if
that, or would you rather have highpaced
trades but more high probability of you
[music] taking losses? So you might take
three or four trades a week, but you
might win two and then win one. And that
one that you win makes back both those
losses plus a little more. There's
different ways on how to balance this
scale. And what I found to be the
perfect time frame to trade on one
specific pair [music]
would be the 4hour time frame. The 4hour
time frame is that perfect medium from
the higher [music] time frame and that
lower time frame where you get that
stronger confirmation but you can also
still get that high pacing move where
within the [music] session you can have
multiple candlesticks close. So the
second step would be picking a time
frame. You can pick again any one of
these time frames. You can pick the 2
hour, 1 hour, 30 minute. Just keep in
mind anything below [music] the 4 hour
will be a bit more volatile and not
[music] as strong as the 4 hour.
Anything above the 4 hour like the day,
the week or the month are [music] much
stronger confirmations but will take
significantly longer to have your
confirmation, [music] your entry signal,
which we'll be breaking down in just a
second. So the 4hour for me is the
perfect middle ground. The perfect
example that I can show you here is this
cell right here for example on EuroUSD.
Right? Just keeping it very simple. I
know if this if you're a beginner, this
might not make sense right away, but I'm
just going to show you an example on the
4 out. Right? So, this is a pattern that
I like to trade a lot, which is the head
and shoulders pattern. You have left
head and then right shoulder. So, this
is a pattern that happens quite
frequently in the market when it tends
to be a reversal pattern. So, there's
multiple ways to trade [music] this
position. You can either take this trade
if you were to sell from the neckline of
this position. So you can have your stop
loss somewhere like this. You can either
enter your trade on the retest of the
neckline of this position so on. Right?
Let's say you'd be looking for this same
exact approach on the daily time frame.
For example, as you can tell here on the
daily time frame if you would have
waited for that head and shoulders
pattern approach, which is [music]
exactly right here. You would have never
gotten that right shoulder that would
have been created in this market for
example. and you would have probably had
to have had a much bigger stop loss. If
you would have entered this trade right
here, your stop loss would have had to
have been [music] bigger. And then your
risk-to-reward in order for you to get a
1 to2, it would have to been
significantly larger. You would have had
to have waited 1 2 [music] 3 4 5 days
for it to get your take to get to your
takerit compared to if you would have
taken this trade off of the 4 hour. This
is the exact same head and shoulders,
the exact same entry. You would have had
your stop loss be somewhere above this
right shoulder and then your takerit
could have been right at this neckline
right here for the 1 to2. It would have
gotten to this in about
1 day and a half. So you could have
waited either 5 days or you could have
waited 1 day and a half. It's the exact
same direction of the trade. You're only
looking for a different stop-loss
placement and a different take-profit
placement. This way you can either have
significantly larger trades or
significantly better timing trades where
they happen a lot faster. [music] So it
really comes down to what approach makes
you feel the most comfortable. Some
people can't wait 5 days in a position.
It's too much [music] time for them.
Some people can't even wait a day and a
half. That might be too much time for
them. So they would have probably had to
have gone down to the one hour, for
example. And in this example right here,
you got [music] another head and
shoulders pattern that happened at this
high point right here. Left head and
then at this right shoulder. They could
have taken the trade either at the break
of this neckline or at this point right
here. The exact same [music] principle
with the stop loss would have been
applied right here. Stop loss could have
been right here. And then [music] this
would have been your take profit for a 1
to2. Perfect for example. This would
have happened in 10 hours. The problem
that people start having now is when
they're seeing these trades, they're
like, "Well, I could have a one hour
entry approach, but then have a day
trade takeprofit." No, that is a big
mistake. And you do not want to do that
because if you're taking a day trade
entry, you stick to a day trade takerit.
If you're taking a scalp or an intraday
trade, you stick to a scalp or an
intraday takerit. Don't crossorrelate
both of them because what will end up
happening is you'll let a massive
winning position for your time frame
that you're trading turn into a losing
position because you're looking for too
[music] much profit. Take your trade on
the one specific time frame on the one
specific pair and that is it. Now that
you have the pair that you are
interested in trading in that correlates
the most with you and you have the
specific time frame that you're looking
to enter this position, you now need to
have a very specific session as when
you're going to take this trade. Now,
keep in mind this session correlates
directly to the actual markets that
you're going to be trading. So, for
example, if you're going to be trading
gold or you're going to be trading the
S&P 500, that's pretty significantly
impacted in New York session because as
soon as the New York Stock Exchange
opens, the S&P 500 moves with the
majority of the US dollars, [music] not
so much in London session. A pair like
gold, you pretty much have it volatile
throughout the entire correlation and
and crossover of London to New York.
[music] And there's other pairs like
GBPUSD which they quite have the impact
significantly more on London session
because the [music] great British pound
is impacted then a pair like Euro USD
for example if I were to pick a session
to take a trade on this pair I would
stick to London session because and
really I would just do London session if
it were to be any market in the industry
because you would have the benefit of
both of the sessions crossover. So, as
you guys can see right here, this is the
time zones of when you have [music] more
and less volume in the market. The
lighter the color is, for example, like
over here, you have less volume means
that the trade in order for it to get to
your takerit will be [music] a lot less.
It's going to take a lot longer. It's
more expensive to trade, and there's
just no real volatility in the market.
No volatility equals no trades or no
movement in the market. The more
volatile you have the market, the more
movements in the market, the better odds
you have of the trade, hitting your
takeprofit a lot faster. Our goal here
is to simply make money as fast as we
possibly can. So, we want to be in the
most volatile moving markets. People
always try and find a reason to take a
trade outside [music] of the session.
And it's just very simple. Do you want
to make money or no? You do. Okay.
You're trading in a time when there's no
money being moved. Nobody's going to is
going to make any money. take a trade at
a session where there's money that's
being moved, you're going to make money.
It's very simple, but people try and
well, what if I can figure out a way on
how to make money in that session? Don't
figure out a way how to make just forget
about it. If there's no volatility
there, leave it to the side and focus on
what [music] matters. And what matters
is these darker sessions because there
is a lot more volatility here. So, I
would look to take a trade either one or
two hours before London session. So it'
be right around here like 1 2 in the
morning my time zone EST. Hold the
position throughout all of London
session and then as soon as New York and
London session have this crossover, this
is where you would have the most
volatility in the market and then hold
it throughout that session if needed for
it to continue to get to my take-profit.
So I would suggest to always stick to
London session. But if you're trading a
pair like the S&P 500 and pairs that are
significantly impacted primarily by the
US, then stick to only trading New York
session. Don't look for a reason to take
a session to take a trade out of
session. You take it before during that
session. And if it hasn't hit your
takerit and there's still significant
influence that it can get to your
takerit, hold it throughout that
session, wait for the next session to
kick in and simply wait, stick to your
plan, set it, forget. So if not, I would
have London session because you just
have the benefit of both. You're
basically entering a trade late if it
has the opportunity of having some
volatility during London session if you
would limit yourself to only taking the
trade during New York session. So this
approach is quite simple and you would
be surprised how many people would
overlook this and still find a reason to
enter a position out of these sessions
and make it make sense for whatever
reason. Do you hold a position that you
entered in London session throughout
Sydney and Tokyo if it has not reached
to your takerit? Yes and no. Yes, if the
market is giving you all the possible
indications that it could still continue
to go to your takerit, just didn't have
enough time there. No, if you're in a
losing position and the weekend is
coming up and you're halfway through
your stop loss, I would probably close
before the market closes because when
market opens on Sunday when the spreads
are quite high, that could simply take
you out at a loss because of the spread.
So, you would want to hold throughout
the session if it hasn't hit your
takerit in that session if there is
still indication that that trade could
make it to your takerit once the next
session kicks in. Perfect example is
let's say I would take a trade on
Tuesday London session. I hold the
[music] position throughout all this
session here with the crossover of New
York and then the trade is halfway to my
take profit. Hasn't had enough momentum
to get there but it's going in my favor.
I say okay you know what I'm going to
continue to hold this position
throughout this Sydney and Tokyo session
until London session kicks in once again
which it should push my trade that other
half that it has left to get to the
takerit. If the trade is halfway through
your stop loss but it's still rejecting,
I would still also continue to hold. So
this approach is quite simple but quite
complex to traders because they just
can't understand [music] the art of
doing nothing in trading is actually
doing something. Letting the trade run,
letting the trade breathe is literally
doing something. It's almost as if you
were to go fishing and you were to hook
a live bait on [music] your hook and you
would cast it out and you just let the
fish swim until sadly a bigger fish
comes and eats it. That time that the
fish is swimming throughout the ocean is
doing something. You're not doing
anything. You're just sitting there on
the boat holding the rod, letting the
fish swim, [music] waiting for another
fish to come eat it. You are actually
doing something by [music] doing
nothing. You're letting the fish go into
the wrong territory until it gets eaten.
And that's where you will then bring in
the bigger fish. That's exactly what
this is [music] like. You're letting the
trade swim. You're letting the trade run
until then it gets to your takerit. And
lastly, and definitely not the most
least, is the entry signal. The entry
signal is what ties [music] all of this
together and it basically makes it a
trade. You can have the perfect pair
that you stick to. You can have the one
time frame you stick to, the one session
you [music] stick to, but you need to
have that one entry reason as to why
you're going to be entering the [music]
position in the first place. This entry
confirmation is quite literally the most
important thing that you need to stick
to consistently. Now, there's tens of
different confirmations and entry
signals out there. You have bullish
engulfings, bearish engulfings, morning
stars, evening stars, dogey rejections,
shooting stars, the book goes on. You
can literally just go on Google and type
in candlestick rejection entry signals
and you're going to get a booklet full
of different ones. Now, this one is
quite peculiar in terms of the selection
of it because it would really come down
to what entry signal do you like the
most? Which one do you see the most
significant on with this specific
market? And this is where you would need
to do a little bit of back testing and
go back and do a little bit of your
research and see which one connects the
most. If I were to recommend you an
entry signal and an approach to stick to
every single time, no matter what,
doesn't matter what day it is, what week
it is, what pair it is, what session it
is, it would come down to these entry
confirmations. And that is going to be
the bullish and bearish engulfing
candlestick confirmations. As you can
tell, an engulfing candlestick or what
the word engulf means is just when
something engulfs something, right? When
it's bigger, the next candlestick in
order for you to enter the position
needs to engulf the last candlestick.
The more candlestick it engulfs, [music]
the better. For example, if I were to be
interested in entering this position as
a buy, this would be a beautiful bullish
engulfing candlestick. This one
candlestick engulfed the last 1 2 3 four
candlesticks. [music] For example, I can
continue to go this way. This is a
bearish engulfing candlestick. has
engulfed the last one and two
candlesticks. This looks like a bullish
candle, but it didn't really engulf
anything other than this small candle.
Down over here, this is not a bullish
engulfing candlestick. Up over here,
this is a bearish engulfing candlestick
that engulfed these last four or five
candlesticks. [music]
This is a bullish engulfing pin bar
candlestick, which just engulfed one
candlestick, [music] which is this last
red candle right over here. This
beautiful bearish engulfing candlestick
engulfed the last 10 candlesticks.
[music] This bullish engulfing
candlestick right here engulfed this
entirety of this consolidation. The
better you have when it comes to an
engulfing candlesticks is [music] the
better it can eat the majority of the
candlesticks to the left. This right
here is probably my favorite type of
engulfing candlestick simply because
what you have here is one candlestick
that has eaten the last [music] 10
candlesticks. has struggled
significantly to break through this
area. So this is the 1 hour time frame.
For example, we're here 1 2 3 4 5 6 7.
So 10 hours you were stuck in this area
and then [music] this one candlestick
eight out of that 10 hours. That gives
me pretty strong indication that it
[music] makes the most sense to take
this position to the upside. Quite
literally that simple. You could have
had a trade play out in your favor. Now,
to summarize everything, we've talked
about having the exact pair that you
should be interested in trading and
sticking to it and not trading any other
pair. Having a one time frame that quite
[music] makes the most sense for you,
where you are in your life, your work,
your routine. Then having a very
specific session, which you look to
[music] enter this trade at all times,
and then an entry signal. Now, I want to
tie all of this together for you guys
just to show you how simple this
approach is and how all you have to do
is just wait. [music] That's it. wait
for this specific approach to present
itself. So for example, here we have the
first step which is [music] having one
market. In this example, we have Euro
USD. So first step is done. Second step
is going to be having the time frame. So
in this specific example, I decided to
pick the 4hour time frame. Second step
is already done. So I'm looking for
entries on the 4hour time frame. So I
need to understand where this time
[music] frame is headed. Is this time
frame headed to the upside? Is it headed
to the downside? And quite very simply,
you can tell that this market is
currently headed to [music] the
downside. In order for you to determine
that, you would need to learn how to
read market [music] structure. This
market structure is currently bearish. A
lot of people might have gotten this
answer wrong if they would have not
known how to read market structure. But
I'll just summarize it very fast. This
at one point was the higher high. This
right here was the higher high. And then
this right here was the higher low right
here. This was the high and the low in
the market, right? If I were to show you
this market like this, that would have
been a very clean higher high and higher
low, right? This is this literally looks
like this over here. Higher high and
higher low. Then we broke below that
higher low, shifting that market to now
being bearish. So, this market structure
is now bearish. Perfect. I've identified
that this market structure is bearish.
Now, I need to be looking for sells. So
this is where I would then be interested
on my next confirmation which is going
to be my entry signal. So I already know
what session I need to be looking for
this trade pre-London session London
session. Now I need to look for my entry
signal. So this is a pattern that's
popping up here. For example, I'm seeing
a head and shoulders left head right
shoulder that's forming right here. What
I would need to wait for is for either
it to break that right shoulder come
back and retest it for me to be
interested in selling. So, as you can
tell, it's right now forming that right
shoulder. Now, we have confirmed broken
that neckline. And I want to wait for
that retest. And my entry confirmation
on that retest would be my engulfing
candlestick right here. This is where I
would have my bearish engulfing
candlestick. My stop loss right here.
And then my take profit could be this
next structure point that's running
around right here to the left. And then
quite literally that simple is exactly
how you would have a trade play out.
You're just watching the direction of
the market. You're following that
direction of the markets and you're
waiting for your engulfing candlestick
in the direction that you have
identified already. It quite really is
that simple. The most important thing is
just being patient and waiting for these
very specific approaches to present
themselves and sticking to it time
[music] and time and time again. And
every single Sunday, I break down the
top markets that I am interested in
trading for the week with my students. I
let them know why this market should
have a direction this way compared to
this way. What are the reasons that I'm
looking to enter a position to the
upside? Where should I be looking to
enter the position to the downside? I
have a community with very successful
traders that we do this every Sunday
with and we review their trade setups
because mistakes are inevitable in
trading and the way for you to scale
[music] and learn is by knowing exactly
what you did wrong. And I was in that
position before like how I told you guys
at the beginning. If I would have been a
perfect success story, I would have gone
from engineer to doctor to trader
because I'd be a genius. But no, I went
from Dunkin Donuts to successful trader
because I learned from [music] zero. And
I learned from my mistakes, but I was
mentored by someone that understood how
I made these mistakes and told me what's
right from wrong. And I do this every
single week with my students that I
share the top trades that I'm interested
in trading. You get to get access to my
strategy if you're part of my community
and much more. You want to learn how to
be part of my community and have me
mentor you and review your trade setups
to make sure that what you're doing is
correct, DM me the word Sunday swings on
the Instagram that the link will be down
below in the description of this [music]
video and we'll make sure that we can
optimize your trading for what your
routine looks [music] like depending on
where you are in the world, which is the
most customizable
benefits of trading that you can have a
specific approach depending on who you
are where you are in the world. So, if
you guys want to know more about this
and become a successful trader, click
the link down below. DM me the word
Sunday Swings on the Instagram down
below. And I hope you guys enjoyed this
video. Hit that like and subscribe
button and I'll see you guys in the next
one. See you guys.